<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thisisjab</title><link>https://thisisjab.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on thisisjab</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:45:30 +0330</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisjab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me</title><link>https://thisisjab.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:45:30 +0330</pubDate><guid>https://thisisjab.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! I am Jab (M. Hossein Jabbarzadeh to be precise). Welcome to my corner of the internet. I’m a final-year Computer Engineering student and a backend engineer with three years of professional experience. This blog is my digital workbench — a place where I document academic deep dives, real-world engineering challenges, and the &amp;ldquo;geeky stuff&amp;rdquo; that keeps me up at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="who-i-am"&gt;Who I Am&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a builder at heart. For me, computers have been the most fascinating &amp;ldquo;toy&amp;rdquo; since childhood, and that curiosity hasn&amp;rsquo;t faded. I want to understand how they work in every aspect: operating systems, networks, and hardware.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hello, friend!</title><link>https://thisisjab.github.io/posts/hello-friend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:42:28 +0330</pubDate><guid>https://thisisjab.github.io/posts/hello-friend/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, friend. (With Elliot Alderson&amp;rsquo;s tone). This is my first writing that I am posting on my corner of the internet—my so-called weblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of starting a blog—writing in general—has always occurred to me. I believe writing is one of the most precious tools ever built by mankind. To me, it feels old, but never outdated. Furthermore, I am tired of this dopamine burst we’re forced through every day. We’ve traded our focus for 15-second loops. Nowadays, people cannot focus for more than 40 seconds (&lt;a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/health/article/attention-spans-shrinking-how-to-regain"&gt;according to this article&lt;/a&gt;) as our attention spans have shrunk due to excessive use of shorts and reels. Machine learning algorithms have evolved to do one thing: keep you scrolling through (all most) junk until your brain rots.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>